<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The infallible guide to travellers or direct independents giving a most exact account of the four principal roads of England, beginning at the Standard, in Cornhill, and extending to the sea-shore, and branching to most of the cities, corporations and market-towns in England and Wales, with their true distance of miles and furlongs, according to Mr. Oglesby's dimensuration / by W.H., Gent.</title>
            <author>W. H., gent.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1682</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 111 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 32 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A43412</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing H155</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R40041</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">18665185</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 18665185</idno>
            <idno type="VID">108134</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A43412)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 108134)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1655:24)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The infallible guide to travellers or direct independents giving a most exact account of the four principal roads of England, beginning at the Standard, in Cornhill, and extending to the sea-shore, and branching to most of the cities, corporations and market-towns in England and Wales, with their true distance of miles and furlongs, according to Mr. Oglesby's dimensuration / by W.H., Gent.</title>
                  <author>W. H., gent.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 57 p., [1] folded leaf of plates : map.  </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for T.B. and are to sold by most booksellers,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1682.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imperfect: stained and cropped, with loss of print.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  Description and travel --  Guidebooks.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-04</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-04</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:108134:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>The Infallible Guide TO TRAVELLERS, OR Direct Independants.</p>
            <p>Giving a moſt Exact Account of the four Principal Roads of <hi>England,</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginning at the Standard in <hi>Cornhill,</hi> and extending to the Sea-Shore, and Branching to moſt of the Cities, Corporations, and Market-Towns in <hi>England</hi> and <hi>Wales,</hi> with their true diſtance of Miles and Furlongs, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to Mr. <hi>Oglesby's</hi> Dimenſuration.</p>
            <p>By <hi>W. H.</hi> Gent.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>T. B.</hi> and are to be ſold by moſt Bookſellers. 1682.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="map">
            <pb facs="tcp:108134:2"/>
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>map of England showing roads, cities, and towns; includes coast of Flanders, Holland, and northeast France, part of Ireland, and part of Scotland</figDesc>
                  <head>A Traveling <hi>Mapp</hi> of <hi>ENGLAND</hi> &amp; Dominon of WALES. by <hi>Iohn Seller</hi> Hidro. to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Kings M.E.</head>
                  <p>Expreſt in y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Mapp by a Black Line Independants.</p>
                  <p>Expreſt by a Prickt Line Prin<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cipal croſs Roads.</p>
                  <p>
                     <list>
                        <item>a Rumford</item>
                        <item>b Ingatſtow</item>
                        <item>c Thaxted</item>
                        <item>d Walden</item>
                        <item>e Sudbury</item>
                        <item>f <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>odſdon</item>
                        <item>g Barnet</item>
                        <item>h S<hi rend="sup">t</hi>. Albans</item>
                        <item>i B<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>ldock</item>
                        <item>k Caxton</item>
                        <item>l Redford</item>
                        <item>m S. Stretford</item>
                        <item>n Ioceſter</item>
                        <item>o Northampton</item>
                        <item>p <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>arentre</item>
                        <item>q Couentre</item>
                        <item>r Stretford</item>
                        <item>ſ Bromſar<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>re</item>
                        <item>t Worchester</item>
                        <item>u Lempſter</item>
                        <item>w Preſtain</item>
                        <item>x Welſhpool</item>
                        <item>y Wrexham</item>
                        <item>z Warington</item>
                        <item>1 Uxbridge</item>
                        <item>2 Amerſham</item>
                        <item>3 Oxford</item>
                        <item>4 Banbury</item>
                        <item>5 Chipping norton</item>
                        <item>6 Campde</item>
                        <item>7 Lamber<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>erſt</item>
                        <item>8 Gloceſter</item>
                        <item>9 Cirenceſter</item>
                        <item>10 Cheſter</item>
                        <item>11 Faringdon</item>
                        <item>12 Malborough</item>
                        <item>13 Caln</item>
                        <item>14 Chippenham</item>
                        <item>15 Whitchurch</item>
                        <item>16 Baſingſtoke</item>
                        <item>17 Guilford</item>
                        <item>18 Stanes</item>
                        <item>19 Henley</item>
                        <item>20 Exeter</item>
                        <item>21 Chedley</item>
                        <item>22 Chegford</item>
                        <item>23 Taveſtok</item>
                        <item>24 Leſtith</item>
                        <item>25 S<hi rend="sup">t</hi>. Blai<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>s</item>
                        <item>26 Brent</item>
                        <item>27 Crookhorn</item>
                        <item>28 Wincheſter</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>A Scale of Miles. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </p>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:108134:3"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:108134:3"/>
            <head>Direct Independants.</head>
            <div type="part">
               <head>
                  <hi>Iter</hi> I. The Road from <hi>LONDON</hi> to <hi>ABERISTWITH,</hi> On the Sea-Coaſt in <hi>Cardiganſhire, South-Wales.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>The General Account.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell>1. THE Point of Bearing</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>W. N. W.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>2. The Direct Horizontal Diſtance</cell>
                        <cell>177 M.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>3. The Vulgar Computation</cell>
                        <cell>145 M.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>4. The Dimenſuration</cell>
                        <cell>199′ 2.</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
                  <table>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">From <hi>LONDON</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell role="label" cols="2">Comp.</cell>
                        <cell role="label" cols="2">Meaſure.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>to Acton</cell>
                        <cell>06</cell>
                        <cell>006</cell>
                        <cell>08′ 3</cell>
                        <cell>008′ 3</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>
                              <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>xbridg</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>09</cell>
                        <cell>015</cell>
                        <cell>10′ 1</cell>
                        <cell>018′ 4</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Beconsfield</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>07</cell>
                        <cell>022</cell>
                        <cell>08′ 5</cell>
                        <cell>027′ 1</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>High Wickham</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>05</cell>
                        <cell>027</cell>
                        <cell>05′ 5</cell>
                        <cell>032′ 6</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Tetſworth</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>037</cell>
                        <cell>12′ 0</cell>
                        <cell>044′ 6</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Iſlip</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>047</cell>
                        <cell>12′ 5</cell>
                        <cell>057′ 3</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Enſton</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>057</cell>
                        <cell>12′ 5</cell>
                        <cell>070′ 0</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Morton in Marſh</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>067</cell>
                        <cell>13′ 2</cell>
                        <cell>083′ 2</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Broadway</cell>
                        <cell>05</cell>
                        <cell>072</cell>
                        <cell>07′ 5</cell>
                        <cell>090′ 7</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Perſhore</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>07</cell>
                        <cell>079</cell>
                        <cell>11′ 6</cell>
                        <cell>102′ 5</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>WORCESTER</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>06</cell>
                        <cell>085</cell>
                        <cell>09.5</cell>
                        <cell>112′ 2</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Bromyard</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>095</cell>
                        <cell>12′ 2</cell>
                        <cell>124′ 4</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Lemſter</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>08</cell>
                        <cell>103</cell>
                        <cell>11′ 3</cell>
                        <cell>135′ 7</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Preſtain</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>08</cell>
                        <cell>111</cell>
                        <cell>12′ 7</cell>
                        <cell>148′ 6</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="2" facs="tcp:108134:4"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>to <hi>Riadergowy</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>14</cell>
                        <cell>125</cell>
                        <cell>21′ 7</cell>
                        <cell>170′ 5</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Brunant</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>135</cell>
                        <cell>13′ 6</cell>
                        <cell>184′ 3</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Aberiſtwith</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>145</cell>
                        <cell>14′ 7</cell>
                        <cell>199′ 2</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>With the Branch to</hi> OXFORD, <hi>Thus:</hi>
                  <table>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">From <hi>LONDON</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell role="label" cols="2">Comp.</cell>
                        <cell role="label" cols="2">Meaſure.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>to Tetſworth</cell>
                        <cell>37</cell>
                        <cell>37</cell>
                        <cell>44′ 6</cell>
                        <cell>44′ 6</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Wheatley</cell>
                        <cell>05</cell>
                        <cell>42</cell>
                        <cell>05′ 4</cell>
                        <cell>50′ 2</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>OXFORD</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>05</cell>
                        <cell>47</cell>
                        <cell>05′ 4</cell>
                        <cell>55′ 6</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>Counties Including the Road, are <hi>Midleſex, Buck<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>inghamſhire, Oxfordſhire, Gloceſterſhire, Worceſter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhire, Herefordſhire, Radnorſhire</hi> and <hi>Cardiganſhire.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Rivers croſt Over, are the <hi>Brent, Coln, Tame, Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wel, Avon, Severn, Teme, Lug, Ithon, Wye, Iſtwith</hi> and <hi>Rydal.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>Forward Ways to be avoided.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">M. F.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 02′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>At the Pound in St. <hi>Giles</hi>'s <hi>LON<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>DON,</hi> the forward Way on the Right to <hi>Hampſted.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>20′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>One Mile 3 Furl. beyond <hi>
                              <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>xbridg,</hi> the Right to <hi>Alesbury.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>34′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>A little ſhort of <hi>Weſt-Wickham,</hi> the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Way on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>35′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>At the end of <hi>Weſt-Wickham,</hi> the Coach Way to <hi>Stoken-Church</hi> on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>49′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>A Furl. beyond <hi>Wheatley</hi> Bridg, the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Way on the Left to <hi>OXFORD.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>52′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>A Furl. beyond <hi>Forreſt Hill,</hi> the Left to <hi>OXFORD.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="3" facs="tcp:108134:4"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 53′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Six Furlongs beyond <hi>Stanton</hi> St. <hi>John Church,</hi> the Right to <hi>Odington.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>65′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Two furl. beyond <hi>Weſton</hi> Church, the Right to <hi>Barton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>73′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>A Mile ſhort of <hi>Chapel on the Heath,</hi> the forward Way on the Left to <hi>Chipping-Norton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>77′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>At the top of the Hill, 2 Furl. beyond <hi>Little Rolwright</hi> Church, the forward Way on the Right to <hi>Long Gompton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>81′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>At the 4 Shire Stone, the Right to <hi>Campden.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>91′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Two Furl. beyond <hi>Broadway,</hi> the Left to <hi>Somerfield.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>95′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Six Furl. ſhort of <hi>Wickenford</hi> Bridg, the Left to <hi>Hinton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>102′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Two Furl. ſhort of <hi>Perſhore,</hi> the Left to <hi>Cheltenham.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>103′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>At the end of <hi>Perſhore,</hi> the Right to <hi>Aulceſter.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>103′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>The Left to <hi>
                              <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>107′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>At the entering <hi>Stouton,</hi> the Left to <hi>
                              <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>p<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton,</hi> the Right to <hi>Eaſton White-Lady.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>123′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Entering <hi>Bromyard</hi> Heath, the Right to <hi>Edwin.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>124′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Entring <hi>Bromyard,</hi> the Left to <hi>HERE<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>FORD.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>125′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>A Mile beyond <hi>Bromyard,</hi> the Left to <hi>Weobley.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>136′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>A Furl. beyond <hi>Lemſter,</hi> the Left to <hi>Weobley.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>138′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Nine Furl. ſhort of <hi>Kingſland</hi> Church, the forward Way on the Left to <hi>Kein<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="4" facs="tcp:108134:5"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 140′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>At the end of <hi>Kingſland,</hi> the Right to <hi>Knighton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>142′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>At the end of <hi>Eaſterton,</hi> the Left to <hi>Hoobden.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>149′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Five Furl. beyond <hi>Preſtain,</hi> the Right to <hi>Knighton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>160′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Two Furl. beyond <hi>Comaron Fluv,</hi> the Right-Hand Way.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>162′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Between the Rivers <hi>Ithon</hi> and <hi>Clowedok,</hi> the Left to <hi>Garthuagh.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>169′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Six Furl. beyond <hi>Dulas Fluv.</hi> the Right to St. <hi>Harmon.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>171′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Two Furl. beyond <hi>Riadergowy,</hi> the Left to <hi>Llanimdoffry.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>175′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Where firſt appears the River <hi>Eland,</hi> the Left to <hi>Roſefair.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>188′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>The Left to <hi>Cardigan.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>190′ 3-</cell>
                        <cell>The Left to <hi>Llanruſted.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>197′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>In <hi>Llanbadern-vaur,</hi> the L. to <hi>Llanruſted</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>The Journal.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">M. F.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 00′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>THe Standard in <hi>Cornhil LONDON:</hi> Whence your Courſe being Weſt, you proceed along <hi>Cornhil,</hi> the <hi>Poultry, Cheapſide, Blowbladder-Street</hi> and <hi>New<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gate-Street,</hi> through <hi>Newgate</hi> and along <hi>Snow-Hill</hi> and <hi>Holborn.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>02′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>The Pound in St. <hi>Giles</hi>'s where you bear to the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>02′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave the Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>02′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>The Lord Mayor's Banqueting-Houſe on the Right, where the Lord Mayor of the
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:108134:5"/> City of <hi>LONDON</hi> Riding to View the Conduit-Heads, is annually Treated.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 03′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Begins <hi>Hide-Park</hi> Wall on the Left, continuing 9 Furl. a little beyond and at the Iſſuing out of the Way to <hi>Padington</hi> ſtands <hi>Tyburn,</hi> the Common Place of Execution of Malefactors for the Cities of <hi>LONDON</hi> and <hi>WESTMINSTER,</hi> and County of <hi>Midleſex.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>04 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Kenſington Gravel-Pits,</hi> a diſcon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinued Village of 4 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>06′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through <hi>Shepperd</hi>'s <hi>Buſh,</hi> a ſmall Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>08′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Acton</hi> of near 3 Furl. a Village of ſome Accomodation.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>11′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Hanwel,</hi> a ſmall Village ſeated on the River <hi>Brent.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>12′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Norcoat,</hi> another ſmall Village of about 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>15′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Hays</hi> Church on the Left 2 Furl.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>15′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Hays,</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs, from the end of which, <hi>Hellingdon</hi> Heath continues, till.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>17′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You enter <hi>Hellingdon,</hi> a ſmall Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>18′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>
                              <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>xbridg</hi> of a Mile in Length, a large, well frequented and Accomodated Market Town; at the End of which you croſs the <hi>Coln</hi> and Enter <hi>Buckinghamſhire.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>23′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You have <hi>Hedgley</hi> Park on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>23′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You Deſcend gently for 4 Furl.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>25′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You Enter a Wood of a Mile upon the Road.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>27′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Beconsfield</hi> of 2 Furlongs, a reaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:108134:6"/> well Accomodated Market-Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 28′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to a Woody Deſcent of 4 F.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>30′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Loudwater</hi> a ſmall Village contiguous on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>32′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>High Wickham</hi> of 3 Furl. Extent, ſeated in a pleaſant Vale; a large, well built and frequented Corporation, Market and Mayor Town; Electing Burgeſſes to Parliament, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>34′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Weſt Wickham</hi> a Village of 2 Furl. and ſome Reception.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>36′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You Aſcend for half a Mile, your Road being Woody on each Hand and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinuing ſo to 38 Miles.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>38′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Oxfordſhire.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>38′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Stoken-Church,</hi> a ſmall but well known Through-fare.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>41′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You Deſcend for 6 Furl. your Road be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Woody on your Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>44′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Tetſworth</hi> of 2 Furl. Length, a well Accomodated Village; whence you have a very direct Way to <hi>Wheatley.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>49′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Wheatley</hi> Bridg, being a fair Stone-bridg of 8 Arches over the River <hi>Tame.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>49′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Here your Road turning ſhort upon the Right, and the direct or forward Way leading to <hi>OXFORD,</hi> you proſecute the latter: and</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>50′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Wheatley,</hi> an indifferent good Town of 3 Furlongs length.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>50′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Croſſing a ſmall Brook you Aſcend for 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="7" facs="tcp:108134:6"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 52′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You Deſcend gently for 10 Furlongs, croſſing a ſmall Rill in the bottom.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>54′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You Deſcend again for 4. Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>55′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the fair River <hi>Charwel,</hi> which riſing in <hi>Northamptonſhire,</hi> paſſes by <hi>Ban<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bury,</hi> and a little below this place unites with the <hi>Thames;</hi> receiving into it, 1ſt. the <hi>Culen,</hi> 2ly. the <hi>Come,</hi> 3ly. the <hi>Tude,</hi> and therein the <hi>Ornus, Sotbrook</hi> and <hi>Oke,</hi> 4ly. the <hi>Swere,</hi> and laſtly the <hi>Reie</hi> or <hi>Bure.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>55′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You actually Enter the Famous City and Univerſity of <hi>OXFORD,</hi> pleaſantly ſeated at the Conflux of the <hi>Charwel</hi> with the <hi>Thames</hi> or <hi>Iſis:</hi> A place of great Anti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quity, large, ſtrong and well-built; and adorn'd with 16 Colleges and 8 Halls, ſhewing a curious Library, a ſtately Thea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter and large Cathedral; beſides 14 Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh Churches: Is Govern'd by a Mayor, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Keeps Courts for all Actions, Elects 4 Burgeſſes to Parliament, has 2 Markets Weekly; Honor'd in its Noble Chancellor <hi>James</hi> Duke of <hi>Ormond,</hi> and in giving Title to the Right Honorable <hi>Aubery Vere</hi> Earl of <hi>OXFORD;</hi> in a word, for its ſtately Schools, Theater and Library, Beautiful Colleges and Halls, Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beral Endowments and plentiful Salaries, for Number of Students and Excellent Oeconomy, the Chriſtian World affords not its Parallel.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>But to proceed.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="8" facs="tcp:108134:7"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 49′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You bear ſhort on the Right, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>51′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Foreſt Hill,</hi> a ſmall Vill. contiguous on the Right only.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>53′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Stanton,</hi> St. <hi>John</hi>'s Church on the Right a Furlong.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>54′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Begin a Wood on the Right for 4 Furl.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>55′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs a Rill over a Stone-bridg, and 2 Furl. farther another.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>55′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Iſlip</hi> Common continuing almoſt to the Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>57′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Over a Stone-bridg of 6 Arches you croſs the <hi>Reie</hi> or <hi>Bure.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>Here you Enter <hi>Iſlip</hi> of a Furlong in length, a ſmall but well Accomodated Town for Reception of Travellers.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>60′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Blechingdon,</hi> a Village of 2 Furl. length.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>62′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Over a Wooden-bridg you croſs the forementioned <hi>Charwel. Pag.</hi> 7</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>62′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>The Right-Hand Way unites again at 64′ 5. but is leſs frequented: The Left-Hand Ways hereabouts leads to that pleaſantly ſituate Corporation and Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket Town, <hi>Woodſtock</hi> about 2 Miles di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>65′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Wotton</hi> Church appears 2 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>66′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Glimton</hi> a ſmall Village, the Left-Hand Ways ſtill leading to <hi>Wood<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtock</hi> aforeſaid; and here you are equally diſtant from <hi>LONDON</hi> and <hi>WOR<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>CESTER.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="9" facs="tcp:108134:7"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 67′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You have <hi>Piddington</hi> Church 3 Furl. to the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>70′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Enſton,</hi> a ſmall Village of about a Furlong long, yet of good Recepti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on: Whence for 3 Miles together your Road is ſtraight and direct.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>73′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>The forward Way on the Left is the di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rect Road to <hi>Chipping-Norton,</hi> a large (though not compact) Corporation and Market-Town, about a Mile and half di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>74′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You have a Houſe contiguous on the Right call'd <hi>Chapel on the Heath.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>74′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Chipping-Norton</hi> lies at Right Angles on the Left about 6 Furlongs diſtant.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>75′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You Deſcend 7 Furl. Aſcending 5 Furl.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>77′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Little Rolwright</hi> Church lies 3 Furlongs on the Left, in which Pariſh about a Mile on the Right ſtands that <hi>Circular Monu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of great Stones;</hi> ſaid to be Erected in Memory of a Battel there fought by <hi>Rollo</hi> the <hi>Dane.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>77′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Begins a Hedg on the Right continuing 3 Furlongs, ſeperating the Counties of <hi>Oxford</hi> and <hi>Warwick.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>79′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Little Compton</hi> Church appears 2 Furl. on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>79′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You Deſcend 4 Furlongs, and ſtill paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing between the ſaid Counties.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>81′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to the 4 Shire Stone, the well known Limits of <hi>Warwickſhire, Oxford<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhire, Worceſterſhire</hi> and <hi>Gloceſterſhire,</hi> which laſt you here Enter.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="10" facs="tcp:108134:8"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 83′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the <hi>Evenlode</hi> which riſing about a Mile higher, Embraces the <hi>Iſis</hi> a bove <hi>OXFORD;</hi> and here preſently you Enter <hi>Morton in the Marſh,</hi> Vulgo <hi>Morton Henmarſh,</hi> of 2 Furlongs; ſeated on the <hi>Foſs-way,</hi> a good Through-fare, though no Market-Town as formerly.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>84′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You Aſcend <hi>Broadway</hi> Hills for 5 Furl.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>85′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Burton on the Hill,</hi> a well Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted Village of 2 Furl.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>85′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Burtons-Aſh</hi> on the Left yielding a ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry fair Proſpect.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>88′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You have a Direction Hand in the Road at the croſs Way to <hi>Winchcomb</hi> on the Left, and <hi>Campden</hi> &amp; <hi>Blockley</hi> on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>89′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You Deſcend <hi>Broadway</hi> Hills aforeſaid, the Deſcent continuing to the Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>90′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Broadway,</hi> a well-built and well Accomodated Town of 5 Furl. Extent.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>92′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Childs Wickham</hi> Church 2 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>96′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Over a Stone-bridg call'd <hi>Wickenford Bridg,</hi> you croſs a Brook and Enter <hi>Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſterſhire;</hi> and a little after the fertile <hi>Vale</hi> of <hi>Eveſholm.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>102′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Over a Stone-bridg of 6 great and ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral ſmall Arches you croſs the fair River <hi>Avon</hi> and Enter <hi>Perſhore,</hi> 7 Furlongs in length; a Town of good Antiquity, large and well frequented, containing 2 Pariſh Churches, and Enjoying 2 Markets Week<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>103′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You have <hi>Alesborough</hi> an Antient Houſe
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:108134:8"/> on the Left, giving the Title of Baron to the Right Honorable the Lord <hi>Coventry.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 107′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Stouton</hi> a ſmall Village of about a Furlong; whence you have a direct Way even to <hi>WORCESTER.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>111′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You Enter the Suburbs, and 3 Furlongs farther through <hi>Sudbury Gate,</hi> the City of <hi>WORCESTER;</hi> a City and County of it ſelf, Pleaſantly and Commodiouſly ſeated on the <hi>Severn:</hi> Of great Antiquity, and Enjoying divers Privileges and Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munities, and though a plentiful Sufferer in Calamities, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> yet ſtill remains a City of much Splendor; ſends Burgeſſes to Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, Gives Title to the Right Noble <hi>Henry</hi> Marqueſs and Earl of <hi>WOR<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>CESTER:</hi> Is an Epiſcopal See Number<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing 88 Biſhops ſucceſſively: Is Govern'd by a Mayor, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Is Divided into 7 Wards, accounting in all, beſides the Cathedral, 11 Pariſh Churches, has 3 Grammer Schools and 7 Hoſpitals; Drives a great Trade in Clothing, which Company be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Conſtituted of <hi>Weavers</hi> and <hi>Walkers</hi> are Incorporated and Confirm'd by Act of Parliament; who either of <hi>Lemſter Ore</hi> or <hi>Spaniſh Wool</hi> make the moſt and Fineſt Cloth in <hi>England:</hi> and has 3 Markets Weekly.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>112′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the foreſaid <hi>Severn</hi> and En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter St. <hi>Johns,</hi> that part of the Suburbs ſo call'd, of 3 Furlongs Extent.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>113′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the ſmall River <hi>Laughern.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="12" facs="tcp:108134:9"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 115′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Cotheridge</hi> Church appears 2 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>117′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Broadwaies,</hi> a ſcattering Village of 2 Furlongs</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>118′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Todnam</hi> Chapel contiguous on the Right</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>119′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Over a Wood-bridg you croſs the <hi>Temde</hi> or <hi>Teme,</hi> which riſing on the Edg of <hi>Radnorſhire,</hi> paſſes by <hi>Knighton, Lud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low</hi> and <hi>Tenbury;</hi> and about two Miles be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low this place falls into the <hi>Severn:</hi> Recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving into it, 1ſt. the <hi>Bradfield;</hi> 2ly. the <hi>Clune,</hi> and therein the <hi>Onke;</hi> 3ly. the <hi>Ony,</hi> and therewith the <hi>Warren</hi> and <hi>Bow, Stad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brook</hi> and <hi>Quenny;</hi> 4ly. the <hi>Corve;</hi> 5ly. the <hi>Ledwich;</hi> 6ly. the <hi>Rea.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>119′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Lulſey</hi> Church lies a little diſtant on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>120′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Herefordſhire</hi> at a little Rill.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>121′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You have Houſes ſcattering on the Road.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>123′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Bromyard Heath</hi> 5 Furlongs over.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>124′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Over a Stone-bridg of 2 Arches you croſs the <hi>Froom</hi> and preſently Enter <hi>Bram<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yard</hi> alias <hi>Bromiard,</hi> of 4 Furl. a large well Accomodated and well frequented Market-Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>127′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Birdonbury,</hi> a ſmall diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>continued Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>130′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Hockly,</hi> a long ſcattering Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>132′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Stein</hi> Bridg over a Brook.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>134′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs by <hi>Eaton</hi> a ſmall Village con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiguous on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>135′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Over a Stone-bridg of 3 Arches you
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:108134:9"/> croſs the <hi>Lug,</hi> and afterward 2 Brooks ſucceſſively.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 135′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Leominſter</hi> vulgo <hi>Lemſter,</hi> only of 4 Furlongs this Way, but a Mile tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſe; a large well built and well Accomo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dated Corporation and Market-Town of about 400 Houſes, Divided into 6 Wards; Govern'd by a Bailiff, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Elects Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament Men, and is Eminent for its Fine Wool call'd <hi>Lemſter Ore.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>139′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave <hi>Kingſland</hi> Church a Furl. on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>139′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the ſmall River <hi>Oncy,</hi> and preſently enter <hi>Kingſland</hi> a diſcontinued Village of 4 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>142′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Eaſterton</hi> a ſmall Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lage of near 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>144′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>145′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You have two or three Houſes on the Road and Hills on your Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>146′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the ſmall River <hi>Wadels,</hi> and enter <hi>Comb</hi> a ſmall Village of about a Furlong.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>148′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You enter <hi>Radnorſhire,</hi> and a Furl. beyond, <hi>Preſtain,</hi> Seated on the River <hi>Lug,</hi> of 4 Furlongs Extent, large, well Built, and well Accomodated; the Shire-Town, enjoying a good Market, and a good Trade in Mault.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>151′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Diſcoyd</hi> a ſcattering Village of 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>153′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs by <hi>Caſcob</hi> a ſmall Village, 2 Furl. farther aſcending a Hill of 6 Furl.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="14" facs="tcp:108134:10"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 154′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You have <hi>Blethuagh</hi> Foreſt on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>154′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend 7 Furlongs, leaving <hi>Ble<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thuagh</hi> Church near a Mile on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>156′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You aſcend 5 Furlongs, deſcending 4.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>159′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs by 2 or 3 Houſes on the Road.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>160′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the ſmall River <hi>Comaron,</hi> aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cending 4 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>160′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend 4 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>161′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the River <hi>Ithon,</hi> falling in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the <hi>Wye</hi> above <hi>Bealt.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>163′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs <hi>Clowedok fluv.</hi> falling into the foreſaid <hi>Ithon.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>164′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs over a little Hill.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>164′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You aſcend a Hill of 4 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>165′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend 6 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>168′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the ſmall River <hi>Dulas.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>170′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Riadergowy</hi> vulgo <hi>Rathader,</hi> o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> 3 Furlongs Extent; Seated on the Rive<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> 
                           <hi>Wye,</hi> but in a Mountainous Part of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> Country, whereby 'tis neither large no<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> plentifully accomodated; yet a Market Town, and Govern d by a Bailiff, <hi>&amp;c<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                           </hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>170′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Over a Wood-bridg you croſs the <hi>Wye</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>171′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You aſcend for 10 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>174′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend 6 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>176′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You aſcend 2 Furlongs, and have th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> River <hi>Eland</hi> parallell to you at 2 Fu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>
                           <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>longs diſtance on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>179′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Croſſing <hi>Ecomiſtwith</hi> Brook, you en<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ter <hi>Cardiganſhire,</hi> and aſcend for 6 Fu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>
                           <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>longs, equally deſcending.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="15" facs="tcp:108134:10"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 183′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs by the Lead-Mines, and 3 Furlongs farther, a Houſe call'd <hi>Mowen-Glowth</hi> on the Right; a Woody Deſcent of 7 Furlongs conveying you to <hi>Brunant.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>184′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through <hi>Brunant</hi> a ſmall Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lage.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>185′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You have 3 or 4 Houſes on the Left, and you aſcend for 10 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>193′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You touch upon the River <hi>Rydal</hi> on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>194′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend for 12 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>196′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the River <hi>Rydal,</hi> and two Furlongs beyond enter <hi>Llanbadern-Vawr,</hi> of 6 Furlongs Extent, well Built, with a fair Church, formerly an Epiſcopal See.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>198′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Aberiſtwith,</hi> Seated on the <hi>Ry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dal</hi> near it's Confluence with the <hi>Iſtwith;</hi> a Corporation, Market and Mayor-Town, Electing one Burgeſs to Parliament; for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merly Wall'd about, and ſtill ſhewing a ruinous Caſtle: Numbers near 100 Hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes; is principally frequented for it's Fiſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Trade, and is oppoſite to <hi>Arclo</hi> in <hi>Ireland.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>Backward Turnings to be avoided.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">M. F.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 198′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>A Furlong from <hi>Aberiſtwith</hi> the Left to <hi>Welſhpool.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>197′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>At the End of <hi>Llanbadern-Vawr</hi> the Left to <hi>Welſhpool.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>194′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>At the Top of the Hill the Right to <hi>Roſefair.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="16" facs="tcp:108134:11"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 193′ 5</cell>
                        <cell>The Right-Hand Way.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>187′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Seven Furlongs ſhort of the Deſcent leading to <hi>Brunant,</hi> the Left to <hi>New-Town.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>169′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Eleven Furlongs beyond <hi>Ryadergowy,</hi> the Left to <hi>Montgomery.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>164′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Nine Furlongs ſhort of <hi>Clowedock fluv.</hi> the Left to <hi>Ludlow</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>161′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>A little ſhort of <hi>Ithon fluv.</hi> the Left to <hi>Knighton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>155′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>At the Foot of the Aſcent leading to <hi>Blethuagh</hi> Foreſt, the Right to <hi>Radnor.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>153′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>At <hi>Caſcob</hi> the Left to <hi>Knighton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>151′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>In <hi>Diſcoyd</hi> and 3 Furlongs beyond, the Right to <hi>Keinton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>148′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Three Furlongs beyond <hi>Preſtain,</hi> the Right to <hi>Keinton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>146′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Two Furlongs beyond <hi>Comb,</hi> the Right to <hi>Keinton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>142′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Three Furlongs beyond <hi>Eaſterton,</hi> the Right to <hi>Arland.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>140′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>In <hi>Kingſland</hi> the Left-Hand Way.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>139′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Two Furlongs beyond <hi>Kingſland,</hi> the Right to <hi>Lawton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>137′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>A Mile ſhort of <hi>Lemſter</hi> the Right to <hi>Evington.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>135′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>In <hi>Lemſter</hi> the Right to <hi>HEREFORD.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>134′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Four Furlongs beyond <hi>Lug</hi> Bridg, the Right to <hi>Hampton,</hi> and a Furlong beyond, the Left to <hi>Pidleſton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>115′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Againſt <hi>Cotheridg</hi> Church the L. to <hi>Hallow</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>110′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Six Furlongs beyond <hi>WORCESTER,</hi> the Left to <hi>Eveſholm.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="17" facs="tcp:108134:11"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 106′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>At the End of <hi>Stouton,</hi> the forward Way on the Right to <hi>
                              <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>105′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>At the End of the Common 14 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs ſhort of <hi>Perſhore,</hi> the Left to <hi>Aul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſter.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>101′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Three Furlongs beyond <hi>Perſhore</hi> Bridg, the Left to <hi>Eveſholm.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>98′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>In the <hi>Vale of Eveſholm,</hi> 2 Miles ſhort of <hi>Wickenford</hi> Bridg, the Right to <hi>Winch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comb.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>86′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Upon <hi>Broadway</hi> Hills, 7 Furlongs ſhort of <hi>Burton</hi>'s <hi>Aſh,</hi> the Right to <hi>Stow.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>80′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>At the Bottom of the Hill, 10 Furl. beyond the 4 Shire-Stone, the Right to <hi>Chipping-Norton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>69′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>At the End of <hi>Enſton,</hi> the Right to <hi>Killington.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>67′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>A Mile ſhort of <hi>Glimpton,</hi> the Right to <hi>Woodſtock.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>66′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>In <hi>Glimpton</hi> the Left to <hi>Banbury.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>64′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Three Furlongs beyond <hi>Wotton</hi> Church, the Left-Hand Way uniting at 62′ 4.</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>In the <hi>OXFORD</hi> Branch.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">M. F.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>54′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>FIve Furlongs from <hi>OXFORD,</hi> the Left to <hi>Heddington.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>51′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Eleven Furlongs ſhort of <hi>Wheatly,</hi> the Right to <hi>Henley.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>In the Road.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">M. F.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>51′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>At <hi>Foreſt-Hill</hi> the Left to <hi>Haulton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="18" facs="tcp:108134:12"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 50′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Nine Furlongs ſhort of <hi>Wheatly</hi> Bridg, the Right to <hi>Wheatley.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>43′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Thirteen Furlongs beyond <hi>Tetſworth,</hi> the Right to <hi>Henley,</hi> the Left to <hi>Aſton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>38′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Seven Furlongs beyond <hi>Stoken</hi> Church, the Left to <hi>Wickham</hi> the Coach-Way.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>18′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>At the End of <hi>
                              <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>xbridg,</hi> the Left to <hi>Swakley.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>17′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Four Furlongs ſhort of <hi>Hellingdon,</hi> the Right to <hi>Colebrook.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>11′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>In <hi>Hanwell</hi> the Right to <hi>Brantford.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="19" facs="tcp:108134:12"/>
               <head>Direct Independants. <hi>Iter</hi> II. The Road from <hi>LONDON</hi> to <hi>ARUNDEL</hi> In <hi>Suſſex.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>The General Account.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell>1. THE Point of Bearing</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>S. W.</hi> b <hi>S.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>2. The Direct Horizontal Diſtance</cell>
                        <cell>49 M.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>3. The Vulgar Computation</cell>
                        <cell>46 M.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>4. The Dimenſuration</cell>
                        <cell>55′ 4.</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
                  <table>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">From <hi>LONDON</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell role="label" cols="2">Comput.</cell>
                        <cell role="label" cols="2">Meaſure.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>to Towting</cell>
                        <cell>05</cell>
                        <cell>05</cell>
                        <cell>06′ 7</cell>
                        <cell>06′ 7</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Ewell</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>06</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>07′ 1</cell>
                        <cell>14′ 0</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Letherhead</cell>
                        <cell>05</cell>
                        <cell>16</cell>
                        <cell>05′ 5</cell>
                        <cell>19′ 5</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Darking</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>04</cell>
                        <cell>20</cell>
                        <cell>04′ 6</cell>
                        <cell>24′ 3</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Stoneſtreet</cell>
                        <cell>05</cell>
                        <cell>25</cell>
                        <cell>05′ 5</cell>
                        <cell>30′ 0</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Billinghurſt</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>35</cell>
                        <cell>11′ 3</cell>
                        <cell>41′ 3</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Amberley</cell>
                        <cell>08</cell>
                        <cell>43</cell>
                        <cell>09′ 7</cell>
                        <cell>51′ 2</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Arundel</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>03</cell>
                        <cell>46</cell>
                        <cell>04′ 2</cell>
                        <cell>55′ 4</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table> Continued from <hi>Arundel</hi> to <hi>Chicheſter 10′ 4.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Midleſex, Surrey <hi>and</hi> Suſſex <hi>include the Road; the</hi> Thames, Mole, Oke, Arun <hi>and</hi> Lavant, <hi>are the Principal Rivers Croſt over.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>* <hi>Note,</hi> there are different Ways to <hi>Arundel,</hi> for ſome will paſs by <hi>Horſham,</hi> others again more frequently by
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:108134:13"/> 
                  <hi>Stretham, Micham</hi> and <hi>Sutton,</hi> and ſo to <hi>Darking.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>Forward Ways to be avoided.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">M. F.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 01′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>AT the End of <hi>Newington,</hi> the Right to <hi>Kingſton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>02′ 3</cell>
                        <cell>At the Gallows the Left to <hi>Croydon.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>08′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>A Furlong beyond <hi>Martin Abby,</hi> the forward Way on the Right to <hi>Kingſton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>13′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Five Furlongs ſhort of <hi>Ewell</hi> the Left to <hi>Nonſuch.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>14′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>In <hi>Ebbeſham</hi> the Right to the Common.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>19′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>In <hi>Letherhead</hi> the Right to <hi>Guilford.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>24′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>In <hi>Darking</hi> the Right to <hi>Guilford.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>32′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>At the Entring <hi>Suſſex,</hi> the Left along <hi>Honey Lane</hi> uniting again; and 4 Furl. beyond, the Right to <hi>Guilford.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>34′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Two Furlongs ſhort of <hi>Rohook</hi> the Left to <hi>Horſham,</hi> and 3 Furlongs farther, the Left by <hi>Screw</hi> Bridg uniting again.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>51′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>A Furlong beyond <hi>Amberley</hi> the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>53′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Six Furlongs beyond <hi>Houghton</hi> the R. to <hi>CHICHESTER.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>The Journal.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">M. F.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 00′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>THe Standard in <hi>Cornhil,</hi> whence you proceed along <hi>Gracechurch-ſtreet, Fiſh-ſtreet-Hill,</hi> over <hi>London-Bridg,</hi> and through <hi>Long Southwark.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>01′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave the Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>01′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Newington</hi> a Village of 2 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs Extent.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="21" facs="tcp:108134:13"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 02′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave the Gallows on the Right, the Place of Execution of Malefactors within the County of <hi>Surrey,</hi> Convicted at <hi>South<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wark.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>05′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs over <hi>Clapham</hi> Heath.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>06′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Towting-beck,</hi> a ſmall Village of 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>06′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Towting-Graveney</hi> another ſmall Village of 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>07′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs a ſmall Rill, paſſing after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards by <hi>Martin Abby</hi> on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>10′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Moredon</hi> a little Village of a Furlong.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>13′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Noneſuch</hi> 2 Furlongs on the Left, a ſtately Houſe of the King's, Built by <hi>H.</hi> 8.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>13′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Ewell</hi> a ſmall Market-Town of 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>15′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Ebbeſham</hi> vulgo <hi>Epſom</hi> well-fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quented for it's Medicinal Waters.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>16′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Epſom</hi> Well lies 3 Furlongs to the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>19′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Leatherhead</hi> a Town of 3 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs and good Reception.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>21′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Mickleham</hi> a Village of 2 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>22′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the River <hi>Mole</hi> near the Place where it makes a ſubterranean Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſage for a Mile or two.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>24′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Darking</hi> or <hi>Darkin,</hi> Situate on a Branch of the <hi>Mole,</hi> a large, well fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quented and well-accomodated Market-Town, extending principally towards <hi>Guil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford</hi> on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="22" facs="tcp:108134:14"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 24′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You aſcend for 2 Furlongs, equally de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcending.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>26′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Aſcend again 3 Furlongs, your Road Woody on each Hand.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>27′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Aſcend <hi>Cold Harbor</hi> Hill 3 Furlongs, deſcending 6 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>29′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Stone-ſtreet</hi> alias <hi>Stanſtreet,</hi> a ſcat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tering Village of 3 Furlongs; whence you have a Cauſeway of 2 Miles, part of the old <hi>Roman Port-way,</hi> call'd <hi>Stany-ſtreet.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>31′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend 2 Furlongs, and come to <hi>Okewood</hi> Bridg over the River <hi>Oke,</hi> equal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly aſcending <hi>Okewood</hi> Hill.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>32′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Having from <hi>London-Bridg</hi> hitherto been in <hi>Surrey</hi> (an Earldom in the Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of <hi>Thomas Howard</hi> Duke of <hi>Norfolk</hi>) you enter <hi>Suſſex.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>35′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Rohook</hi> a ſmall Village contiguous on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>35′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You enter a Wood of 3 or 4 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>36′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the River <hi>Arun,</hi> leaving <hi>Det<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſum Place</hi> 2 Furlongs on the Left between this and the other Way by <hi>Screw-Bridg;</hi> the Left-Hand Ways hereabouts lead to that handſom Corporation, Market &amp; Shire Town, <hi>Horſham,</hi> about 2 Miles diſtant.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>39′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Buckman-Corn,</hi> 2 or 3 Houſes ſo call'd.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>41′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Billinghurſt</hi> of 3 Furlongs and good Accomodation.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>43′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through <hi>Mulſey</hi> a little diſcon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinued Village, and 2 Furlongs farther over <hi>New-Bridg.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="23" facs="tcp:108134:14"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 45′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs over <hi>Pulborow</hi> Common.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>45′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Deſcend for 3 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>46′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Wickford</hi> Bridg, leaving <hi>Pulborow</hi> Church a Mile on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>47′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Wickenholt</hi> a Village of a Furl. length; 2 Furlongs beyond which begins <hi>Parham</hi> Park contiguous on the Left, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tending 11 Furlongs, and encloſing near the farther End the Place or Manor-Houſe of the ſame Name.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>50′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through <hi>Parham</hi> a ſmall ſcat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tering Village; whence you have a deſcent of 2 Furlongs, ſeconded by 2 others of the like quantity.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>51′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Amberley</hi> an indifferent Thorough-fare of 3 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>52′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Over <hi>Houghton</hi> Bridg you croſs the <hi>Arun,</hi> continuing thence on your Left to <hi>Arundel.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>52′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Houghton</hi> a Village of 2 Furl.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>54′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You aſcend for 3 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>55′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Arundel</hi> by the Way of <hi>Mary-Gate,</hi> about 6 Furlongs long; an Anti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent, well-frequented and accomodated Corporation, Market and Seaport-Town, Seated on the <hi>N. W.</hi> of the River <hi>Arun,</hi> and having on It's Eaſt Side a large and Eminent Caſtle, on whoſe Poſſeſſion is Entail'd the Earldom of <hi>Arundel,</hi> now in the Perſon of <hi>Thomas Howard</hi> Duke of <hi>Norfolk.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <pb n="24" facs="tcp:108134:15"/>
                     <head>The Continuation to <hi>Chicheſter.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">M. F.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 00′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>ENter the Old Fiſh-Market in <hi>Arun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>del,</hi> proceeding through the <hi>Water-Gate.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>00′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Begins <hi>Arundel</hi> great Park on the Right, extending 9 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>02′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Deſcend <hi>Amsford</hi> Hill of 4 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>04′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Mackrel</hi>'s Bridg.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>04′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs by Half-way Tree.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>06′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through <hi>Crockerhil</hi> a ſmall Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>07′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You have <hi>Boxgrove</hi> Church and Hall a little on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>08′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through <hi>Maudlin</hi> a ſcatter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>08′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs between <hi>Hampnet</hi> Church on the Right, and the Place on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>09′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the <hi>Lavant.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>09′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter the Suburbs of <hi>CHICHESTER,</hi> antiently <hi>Ciſſanc-Caſter,</hi> Seated on the fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid <hi>Lavant</hi> near It's Influx into the Sea; a City indifferent large, numbring 4 Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh-Churches within the Walls beſides the Cathedral, and 4 Gates reſpecting the 4 Cardinal Points: Is Govern'd by a Mayor, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Elects Parliament-Men, and it's Markets are Noted for the beſt Fiſh-Markets in the County.</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <pb n="25" facs="tcp:108134:15"/>
                     <head>Backward Turnings to be avoided.</head>
                     <head>In the Branch.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">M. F.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 08′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>AT the End of <hi>Maudline</hi> the Left to <hi>Petworth.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>In the Road.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">M. F.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 51′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>IN <hi>Amberley</hi> the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>37′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Nine Furlongs ſhort of <hi>Arun fluv.</hi> the Right by <hi>Screw-Bridg</hi> uniting at 35′ 2.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>34′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Seven Furlongs beyond <hi>Rohook</hi> the Right along <hi>Honey-Lane</hi> uniting at 32′ 7.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>24′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>A Furlong beyond <hi>Darking</hi> the Right to <hi>LONDON</hi> by <hi>Stretham.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>19′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>In <hi>Leatherhead</hi> the Left to <hi>Kingſton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>14′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Entring <hi>Ewell</hi> the Left to <hi>Kingſton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="26" facs="tcp:108134:16"/>
               <head>Direct Independants. <hi>Iter</hi> III. The Road from <hi>LONDON</hi> to <hi>BARWICK</hi> In <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>The General Account.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell>1. THE Point of Bearing</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>N.</hi> b. <hi>W.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>2. The direct Horizontal Diſtance</cell>
                        <cell>280 M.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>3. The Vulgar Computation</cell>
                        <cell>260 M.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>4. The Dimenſuration</cell>
                        <cell>339 M. 2 F.</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>Counties paſt through, <hi>Midleſex, Hartfordſh. Cambridgſh. Huntingdonſh. Rutlandſh. Lincolnſh. Not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinghamſh. Yorkſh.</hi> the Biſhoprick of <hi>Durham,</hi> and <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Rivers Croſt over are, the <hi>Lea, Granta, Owſe, Nine, Welland, Witham, Trent, Meden, Idle, Whitwater, Dun, Went, Are, Wharf, Nid, Your</hi> or <hi>Owſe, Swale, Wisk, Tees, Skern, Were, Tyne, Blith, Wanspeck, Ale, Warn, Tweed.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>The Journal.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">M. F.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 00′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>THe Standard in <hi>Cornhil, LONDON,</hi> whence you proceed along <hi>Biſhops-Gate-ſtreet</hi> within, through <hi>Biſhops-Gate, Biſhops-gate-ſtreet</hi> without, and <hi>Shoreditch.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="27" facs="tcp:108134:16"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 01′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>* At <hi>Shoreditch</hi> Church the Right to <hi>Hackney.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>01′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave the Town, <hi>Hogſdon</hi> appearing a Furlong to the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>02′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Kingſland</hi> a Village of a Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>long.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>02′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Iſtington.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>03′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Newington</hi> a Village of 2 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs, the Church about a Mile on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>03′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to a gentle Aſcent for 4 Furlongs call'd <hi>Stanford-Hill,</hi> as gently deſcending to 4′ 5.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>04′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>** On <hi>Stanford</hi> Hill the Left to <hi>Hack<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>95′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Tottenham-High-Croſs</hi> of about 3 Furlongs, a Village well-frequented by Citizens.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>06′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Having firſt paſt ſeveral Houſes on the Road and the Church on the Left, you enter <hi>Tottenham-Street</hi> of near 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>07′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Edmonton</hi> a long diſcontinued Village, the Church on the Left 2 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>08′ 5..</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Ponders-End</hi> a ſmall Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>09′ 1</cell>
                        <cell>You enter <hi>Lackmore-End</hi> another Ham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>let of about 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>10′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Enfield-Waſh</hi> a long diſunited Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>10′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>** In <hi>Enfield-Waſh</hi> avoid the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>12′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Firſt leaving <hi>Tuttle-ſtreet</hi> on the Left half a Mile, you enter <hi>Hartfordſhire,</hi>
                           <pb n="26" facs="tcp:108134:17"/>
                           <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                              <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                           </gap>
                           <pb n="27" facs="tcp:108134:17"/>
                           <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                              <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                           </gap>
                           <pb n="28" facs="tcp:108134:18"/> and therewith <hi>Waltham-Croſs</hi> of 3 Furl. near a Mile to the Right of which, and on the other ſide the <hi>Lea,</hi> is the Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket-Town of <hi>Waltham-Abby.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 13′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Having left <hi>Theobalds</hi> a Houſe of the Kings on the Left, you come to <hi>Croſs<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brook,</hi> and 2 Furlongs beyond, <hi>Turners-Hill,</hi> ſmall Villages.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>13′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>** In <hi>Turner</hi>'s <hi>Hill</hi> avoid the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>14′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Cheſton-ſtreet</hi> 2 Furl. the Church half a Mile on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>16′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Wormeley-End</hi> of 2 Furlongs, the Church a quarter of a Mile on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>16′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Croſs the New River diſcourſt of in the beginning of the Road from <hi>LON<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>DON</hi> to <hi>Holyhead.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>16′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Brockton</hi> a Village of a Furlong Extent.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>17′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>After an eaſie Deſcent you enter <hi>Hodſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> of above 6 Furl. Extent, Seated on the Weſt of the <hi>Lea,</hi> a well-frequent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Market-Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>17′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>* To <hi>Broctonbury-Hall.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>19′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Hayley</hi> Church a little on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>20′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Amwel</hi> a ſmall Village, from which and <hi>Chadwel</hi> another adjacent Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lage, the foreſaid New River is convey'd to <hi>LONDON.</hi> The Left-Hand Ways hereabouts lead to <hi>Hartford</hi> the Shire-Town, about 2 Miles diſtant; a Marqui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſate and Earldom in the Perſon of <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Seymour</hi> Duke of <hi>Somerſet.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="29" facs="tcp:108134:18"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>* Avoid the Right-Hand Way.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 21′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Hartford.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>21′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Ware</hi> a Mile in Length, at the hither End whereof, you firſt croſs the ſaid New-River, and next the foreſaid <hi>Lea;</hi> for which <hi>vid. the Road from</hi> Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don <hi>to</hi> Harwich: The Town is large, of good Reception and a handſom Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>23′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs by <hi>Wades-Mill,</hi> where you croſs the <hi>Mimer</hi> a Branch of the <hi>Lea.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>24′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Paſs through <hi>High-Croſs-End</hi> a ſmall Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>25′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>After an eaſie Deſcent you paſs through <hi>Colliers-End</hi> another Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>* The Right to <hi>Standon.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>27′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Puckrich</hi> or <hi>Puckeridg</hi> of 3 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs Length; a Mile to the Right of which is <hi>Standon</hi> a Market-Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>27′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Leaving <hi>Puckrich,</hi> the Road to <hi>Cam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bridg</hi> and <hi>Kings-Lyn</hi> on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>29′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Repaſs the <hi>Mimer.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>31′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Buntingford</hi> a Market and good Thorough-fare Town of 3 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>33′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>through <hi>New-Chipping</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>34′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Buckland</hi> another Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>38′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>After an eaſie Deſcent you enter <hi>Roy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton,</hi> Seated upon the <hi>Ermin-ſtreet,</hi> near the Edg of the County, Part of it being in <hi>Cambridgſhire;</hi> a large Town of 4 Furlongs Extent, enjoying a good Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket for Corn: Here the Poſt goes off to <hi>Cambridg,</hi> &amp;c.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="30" facs="tcp:108134:19"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 39′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Cambridgſhire.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>40′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Kneeſworth</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>43′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Croſs the <hi>Grant</hi> or <hi>Cam</hi> which runs by <hi>Cambridg.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>44′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Arrington</hi> a Village of a Furlong.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>45′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Wimple</hi> a little on the Right, and at 46′ 2. <hi>Cungrave</hi> on the ſame Hand.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>47′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left to <hi>Packſton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>47′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter a little Wood of 4 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>48′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Packſtone.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through <hi>Holm</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>49′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left-Hand Way to <hi>Bourn.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>49′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Caxton</hi> of 3 Furlongs Length, a Market and Poſt-Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>51′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Papworth Everard</hi> a Village of 2 Furl. and at 53′ 3. leave <hi>Neather Pap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth</hi> or <hi>Papworth Agnes,</hi> about half a Mile on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>53′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Huntingdonſhire.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>55′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs by <hi>Beggars-Buſh,</hi> Seated on an Eminence, a Buſh ſo call'd.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>56′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>After a ſmall Deſcent you enter <hi>God<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mancheſter</hi> of 4 Furlongs; a Corporation large and antient; and here you have a Way to <hi>Cambridg</hi> 12 Miles off.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>57′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the River <hi>Owſe,</hi> for which (<hi>vid.</hi> LONDON <hi>to</hi> King's-Lyn) and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter <hi>Huntingdon,</hi> a well-frequented Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poration, Market and Shire-Town, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taining 4 Churches, heretofore 15. Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tends about 6 Furlongs on the Road;
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:108134:19"/> Elects Parliament-Men, and gives Title to the Right Honorable <hi>Theophilus Haſtings</hi> Earl of <hi>Huntingdon.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 58′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>* At the End of <hi>Huntingdon</hi> Leave the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>59′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Great Stukely</hi> a Village of 2 Furl.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>60′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Paſs through <hi>Little Stukely.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>64′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Paſs by <hi>Stonegate-Hole</hi> a Houſe on the Left; and at 65′ 0. <hi>Stonegate</hi> a Houſe on the Left alſo.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>65′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left to St. <hi>Ives.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>66′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave St. <hi>Andrews</hi> Chapel a little on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>67′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Cunnington</hi> 2 Furlongs on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>69′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Stilton</hi> of 3 Furlongs Extent, a Poſt-Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Oundle</hi> and the Left to <hi>PETERBORO<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>GH.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>73′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs between <hi>Cheſterton</hi> on the Left, and <hi>Allerton</hi> on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>73′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>* A Way to <hi>Allerton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Waſhington Corner.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>73′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left forward Way to <hi>PETER<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>BORO<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>GH.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>74′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Water-Newton</hi> a Village of two Furlongs, Situate on the Southern Banks of the <hi>Nine.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>76′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through <hi>Sibſon</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>77′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Croſs the <hi>Nine</hi> aforeſaid, and enter <hi>Northamptonſhire,</hi> and therewith, <hi>Walms<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford</hi> of 2 Furlongs Extent.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>77′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>** The right-forward Way to <hi>Stilton</hi> a different Way.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="32" facs="tcp:108134:20"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 80′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Wittering</hi> 2 Furl. on the Left; and at 81′ 4. the Left forward.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>82′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Having firſt paſt between <hi>Wolthrop</hi> and <hi>Burleigh</hi> Halls, you enter <hi>Stamford,</hi> Seat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed on the <hi>Welland,</hi> and in the County of <hi>Lincoln</hi> at It's Conjunction with <hi>Rutland</hi> and <hi>Northamptonſhire;</hi> an antient, large and floriſhing Corporation and Market-Town, of 5 Furlongs Length, Electing Parliament Men; was formerly an Uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſity, and now gives Title to the Right Honorable <hi>Henry Grey</hi> Earl of <hi>Stamford.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>83′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left to <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ffington.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>83′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Rutland.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>84′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right or forward Way which unites again at 81′ 4.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>85′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Croſſing a ſmall Rill you enter <hi>Bridg-Caſterton</hi> of 2 Furlongs Length.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>86′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>You have <hi>Tickingcote</hi> 2 Furl. on the Left; and at 89′ 6. <hi>Greetham</hi> at the like diſtance on the ſame Hand.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>90′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Paſs through a ſmall Wood.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>91′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Stratton</hi> 2 Furl. on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>91′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>** Oppoſite to <hi>Stratton</hi> avoid the Right, and the Left to <hi>Stratton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>92′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Paſs through another little Wood.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>92′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Lincolnſhire.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>94′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Through <hi>Poſt-Witham</hi> alias <hi>North-Wi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tham,</hi> of 2 Furlongs; or you may leave it half a Mile on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>96′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Buckminſter,</hi> the Left to <hi>Corbey.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>96′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Through <hi>Coltſworth</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="33" facs="tcp:108134:20"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 97′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Croſs the River <hi>Witham,</hi> taking it's Riſe a Mile or two above.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>97′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Right to <hi>Eaſton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>98′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You have a ſmall Deſcent and a Rill in the Bottom.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>98′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Kirk-Stoke,</hi> the Left to <hi>Eaſton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>101′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Great Paunton</hi> a Village of near 2 Furlongs, Seated near the <hi>Wi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tham,</hi> and of good Antiquity.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>102′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Little Paunton</hi> 2 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>103′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left to <hi>Boſton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>104′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Paſs by the <hi>Spittle</hi> or <hi>Hospital</hi> on the Left, and a few Houſes on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>104′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Grantham,</hi> Seated low, and on the Weſtern Banks of the <hi>Witham;</hi> a large and well-frequented Corporation and Market-Town of 4 Furlongs Extent, with a fair Church and good Free-School, and the Election of Parliament Men.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>104′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left to <hi>Barobey.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>105′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You aſcend gently 3 Furlongs, and then croſs a ſmall Rill, paſſing between the Gal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lows on the Left, and a Wind-Mill on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>106′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Your Aſcent continuing hitherto, you come to <hi>Gunnerby</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>106′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend <hi>Hoocliff</hi> Hill for 2 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>109′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Allington</hi> 2 Furl. on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>109′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right forward Way.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>109′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Foſton</hi> of near 3 Furlongs Extent.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="34" facs="tcp:108134:21"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 111′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left to <hi>Weſtburrow.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>111′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You arrive at <hi>Bennyngton</hi> a diſcontinu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Village of a Mile in Length.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>112′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Right to <hi>Dodington.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>113′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left to <hi>Dodington.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>114′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Nottinghamſhire.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>116′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Balderton</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>117′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>** Avoid the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>118′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Firſt paſſing by the Gallows, avoid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Way on the Right to <hi>Codington,</hi> you enter <hi>Newark</hi> Seated on the South-Eaſt Side of the <hi>Trent,</hi> a large, well-fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quented Corporation and Market-Town of 6 Furl. in Length; hath it's Repreſenta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tives in Parliament, and the Ruins of a once ſtately Caſtle.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>118′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Over a fair Bridg you croſs the <hi>Trent</hi> aforeſaid.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>119′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left to <hi>Kellum.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>120′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Kellum.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>120′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs a ſeparated Branch of the <hi>Trent,</hi> which uniting again, forms an I<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſland of 2 Miles long, and half ſo broad.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>121′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>South-Muſcomb</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>122′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs by <hi>North-Muſcomb</hi> conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guous on the Right, Seated on the Banks of the <hi>Trent.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>123′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Crumwell,</hi> on the Banks of the <hi>Trent</hi> alſo, a Village of 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>124′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs a ſmall Rill falling into the adjacent <hi>Trent.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>125′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Carlton upon Trent,</hi> a ſmall Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="35" facs="tcp:108134:21"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 125′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Norwel.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>127′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through <hi>Sutton</hi> another ſmall Village, Seated likewiſe on the <hi>Trent,</hi> which afterwards winds off to the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>128′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through <hi>Weſton</hi> a ſmall Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lage.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>130′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Right to <hi>Normanton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>130′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left to <hi>Normanton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>131′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Tuxford in the Clay</hi> of 3 Furl. Length, an indifferent Market and Poſt-Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>132′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Little Markham</hi> 2 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>133′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You have a ſmall Deſcent and a Bea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>con on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>** On the Beacon Hill avoid the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>133′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the <hi>Idle</hi> falling into the <hi>Dun.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>134′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Through <hi>Weſt</hi> (or <hi>Little) Draiton</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>134′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>** Avoid the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>134′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Croſs a ſmall Rill falling into the ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jacent <hi>Idle,</hi> and enter the Foreſt of <hi>Sher<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wood.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>134′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left to <hi>Elſey.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>135′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Elſey</hi> Church a little on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>137′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Paſs by the 4 Oaks.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>138′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Babworth</hi> a little on the Right, and <hi>Redford</hi> a Market-Town at about a Miles diſtance on the ſame Hand, upon the foreſaid <hi>Idle.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>141′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Right to <hi>Sutton,</hi> the Left acute.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>141′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Barnby on the Moor,</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="36" facs="tcp:108134:22"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 142′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Through <hi>Turworth</hi> a Village, leaving <hi>Blith</hi> a Market-Town a Mile to the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>143′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Ravenskel</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>145′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Scrooby</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>145′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>** Avoid the Right-Hand Way.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>146′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs <hi>Whitwater Fluv.</hi> near its Conjunction with the <hi>Idle,</hi> and Enter <hi>Yorkſhire,</hi> and <hi>Bautre</hi> a ſmall Market-Town of 3 Furl. Traded unto for <hi>Mill<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtones,</hi> &amp;c.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>148′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through a little Wood.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>151′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Open Way conveys you to <hi>Roſſington</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>151′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Right to <hi>Cantley.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>151′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>** In <hi>Roſſington</hi> the Right to the Church</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>151′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>153′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>High Eaders</hi> 2 Furl. on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>153′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left to <hi>Cantlow.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>155′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Doncaſter</hi> of 5 Furlongs length, ſituate on the River <hi>Dun,</hi> an Antient, large, well-built and well frequented Corporati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on and Market-Town; Traded unto for <hi>Knit-Waſtcoats, Stockins,</hi> &amp;c.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>155′ 5-</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the <hi>Dun</hi> aforeſaid, falling in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the <hi>Are</hi> near <hi>Snathe.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>156′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave <hi>Cuſworth</hi> 2 Furl. on the Left, at 157′ 2. <hi>Scausby,</hi> and at 158′ 0. <hi>Pigborn,</hi> all at the like Diſtance and on the ſame Hand.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>156′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left to <hi>Scausby.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>160′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right the Street Way, the Left to <hi>Adam-ſtreet.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>161′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs by <hi>Robin-Hood</hi>'s Well.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="37" facs="tcp:108134:22"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 162′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Skelburrow.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>165′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Wentbridg</hi> a Town of 2 Furl. in the midſt whereof you croſs the <hi>Went</hi> falling into the <hi>Dun</hi> near <hi>Snath</hi> aforeſaid.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>166′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>167′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Right to <hi>Womerley.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>167′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through <hi>Darrington</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>170′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Ferrybriggs</hi> of 3 Furlongs, a Poſt Town Situate on the South Side of the broad River <hi>Are</hi> (which falls into the <hi>Owſe</hi> near <hi>Howden</hi>) paſſable by a fair Stone-Bridg, beyond which the Left-Hand Way to <hi>Boroughbridg</hi> by <hi>Abyforth</hi> and <hi>Wetherby</hi> meaſures 9 Miles leſs than that by <hi>YORK.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>171′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left to <hi>Brotherton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>You leave <hi>Brotherton</hi> 2 Furlongs on the Left, and at 172′ 2. <hi>Burton</hi> a like diſtance on the ſame Hand.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>172′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Right to <hi>Hillum.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>172′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left to <hi>Pool</hi> and a Furlong far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther the Right to <hi>Burton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>173′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend <hi>Bettereſs</hi> Hill of 2 Furl.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>174′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Milford</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>176′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Firſt croſſing a Branch of the <hi>Wharf,</hi> you arrive at <hi>Sherborn</hi> 4 Furl. Long; a Market-Town, with a good Free-School, and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bounding in Cherries.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>177′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave <hi>Barkſton,</hi> and at 178 <hi>Scar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thingwel</hi> Hall, each 2 Furl. on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>179′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You arrive at <hi>Tolton</hi> vulgo <hi>Towton,</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs, Eminent for a great Battel between the Houſes of <hi>York</hi> and <hi>Lancaſter, Anno</hi> 1461.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="38" facs="tcp:108134:23"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 182′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Wingate.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>182′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Over a Stone-Bridg you croſs the fair River <hi>Wharf,</hi> falling into the <hi>Owſ</hi> near <hi>Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wood,</hi> and enter <hi>Tadcaſter</hi> an antient well-provided Market-Town of 3 Furl. Length, and affording plenty of Lime-Stone.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>185′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Tadcaſter</hi> the Street-Way.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>185′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Street-Houſes</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs: whence little occurs till at</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>190′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You reach <hi>Ring-Houſes</hi> a Village of near 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>191′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You have the Gallows on the Right, and a little after 2 Wind-Mills on the Right and one on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>191′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Green-Hammerton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>191′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You enter the Suburbs of the City of <hi>YORK.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>192′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You enter <hi>Mickle-Gate</hi> and therewith the City it ſelf; 2 Furlongs farther you come to <hi>Owſe</hi> Bridg, and at 192′ 4. you arrive at the Pavement or Midle of the Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty:</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>The Second of the Kingdom, Seated on the Navigable <hi>Your</hi> or <hi>Owſe;</hi> well-built, and Fortify'd with a Caſtle and Walls, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tending each way about 12 Furl. containing within it's 4 Wards 32 Pariſh Churches and the Cathedral, a large and Magni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficent Structure with a curious Chapter-Houſe: Govern'd by a Lord Mayor, 12 Aldermen, Juſtices, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Is repreſented by two Burgeſſes in Parliament; and gives
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:108134:23"/> Title to the moſt Illuſtrious <hi>James</hi> Duke of <hi>York.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 192′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left forward to <hi>LONDON.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>Continuing our Dimenſuration from <hi>Mickle-Gate</hi> aforeſaid, you repeat 3 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs of the Road back again.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>194′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Right to <hi>Popleton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>194′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Popleton</hi> 2 Furl. on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>195′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs by a Blue Stone adjoyning the Road on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>196′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Heſley</hi> 3 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>198′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>More-Monkton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>199′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Over <hi>Skip-Bridg</hi> you croſs the <hi>Nid,</hi> falling into the <hi>Owſe</hi> a little below.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>201′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Kirk-Hammerton</hi> 2 Furl. on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>201′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Kirk-Hammerton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>201′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Through <hi>Green-Hammerton</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>202′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Whixley</hi> 2 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>204′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Little</hi> 2 Furlongs on the Right, near which the foreſaid <hi>Owſe</hi> takes Riſe, and preſently unites with the <hi>Your.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>206′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Branton-Green</hi> on the Right, and at 206′ 5. <hi>Grafton</hi> on the Left, equally 2 Furlongs diſtant from the Road.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>208′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>** Avoid the Right; and at 209′ 2. the Right to <hi>Wetherby.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>209′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Having firſt left <hi>Aldborough,</hi> that old <hi>Roman</hi> City 3 Furlongs on the Right, you fall in with the Road from <hi>Ferrybriggs</hi> by <hi>Wetherby</hi> aforemention'd, and enter <hi>Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>roughbriggs</hi> of 3 Furlongs Length, a Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poration
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:108134:24"/> and Market-Town, with the E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lection of Parliament Men; at the End of which you croſs the <hi>Your</hi> aforeſaid.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 209′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left to <hi>Wetherby,</hi> the Right to <hi>Aldborough.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>210′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left to <hi>Humberton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>213′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through <hi>Disford</hi> a ſmall Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lage.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>* The Left to <hi>Rippon.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>214′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>In <hi>Leeming</hi> Lane you fall in with a Right-Hand Way from <hi>YORK,</hi> which coming to <hi>LONDON</hi> is your Left-Hand Way to be avoided.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>214′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left to <hi>Rippon.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>215′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You enter <hi>Topcliff</hi> eminently Situate on the Banks of the <hi>Swale,</hi> a Thorough-fare of about 5 Furlongs length.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>215′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>** A little beyond the Bridg avoid the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>217′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Newby</hi> Hall 2 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>218′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Catton on the Moor</hi> a Village of near 3 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>220′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave <hi>Skipton</hi> on the Left 3 Furl. and <hi>Carleton</hi> a little diſtance on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>221′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through <hi>Sand-Heuton,</hi> leav<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing <hi>Thresk</hi> a Market and Burrough-Town 12 Furl. on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>223′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Newſom,</hi> and 6 Furlongs beyond, <hi>Kirkby,</hi> each 2 Furlongs on the Left, and upon the Banks of the <hi>Wisk.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>225′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Great</hi> (or <hi>South) Ottrington,</hi> and at 226′ 3. <hi>Little Ottrington,</hi> each 2 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:108134:24"/> on the Left, and on the foreſaid <hi>Wisk.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 229′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left to <hi>Thresk.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>229′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Northallerton</hi> Seated on a Branch of the <hi>Wisk,</hi> a large, well-built, Market, Borough and Poſt-Town; Electing Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geſſes to Parliament.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>231′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Danby.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>233′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Lowſey-Hill</hi> a Village cloſe on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>235′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Little Smeton</hi> of near 2 Furlongs, at the End of which you croſs the fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mention'd <hi>Wisk.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>235′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Great Smeton</hi> another Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>239′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend <hi>Break-Horſe Bank,</hi> and 4 Furlongs beyond, leave <hi>Erey</hi> Hall a little on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>240′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs the <hi>Tees,</hi> enter the Biſhop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rick of <hi>Durham,</hi> and therewith <hi>Nyſome</hi> a Village of near 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>242′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left to <hi>Yarum.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>243′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the <hi>Skern,</hi> a little below fall<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing into the foreſaid <hi>Tees;</hi> and enter <hi>Dar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lington</hi> vulgo <hi>Darnton</hi> of 5 Furl. length, a Market and Poſt-Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>245′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left to the Coal-Pits.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>** The Left to <hi>Barmetton.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>247′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You enter <hi>Coleham</hi> or <hi>Coton Mundhil,</hi> of near 2 Furlongs, Seated on the foreſaid <hi>Skern.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>249′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>** Avoid the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>249′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Acle</hi> or <hi>Ackham</hi> a Village of near 2 Furl. alſo.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="42" facs="tcp:108134:25"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 252′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Woodham</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>253′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You arrive at <hi>Ruſhy</hi> Ford over a ſmall Branch of the adjacent <hi>Skern,</hi> half a Mile to the Right of which appears <hi>Windleſtone,</hi> and about 2 Miles diſtance on the ſame Hand, at the Confluence of the <hi>Gaunleſs</hi> with the <hi>Were,</hi> lies <hi>Biſhops Aukland,</hi> a Market-Town with a fair Seat of the Bi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhops of <hi>Durham,</hi> curiouſly repair'd, and and a ſtately Chapel Built by the late Worthy and Reverend Father Doctor <hi>John Cozens</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Durham.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>254′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left to <hi>Great Merington.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>255′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Weſt Cloſe</hi> Houſe a little on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>255′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Leaving <hi>Little Chilton</hi> 2 Furlongs on the Right; you enter <hi>Ferry ſuper Montem,</hi> vulgo <hi>Ferry-Hill,</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs, Seated on the Pitch of a Deſcent.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>259′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Sunderland</hi> a Village con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiguous on the Right, at the End of which you croſs the foremention'd <hi>Were.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>262′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>** Avoid the Left forward.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>262′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter the Weſtern Suburbs of <hi>D<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>R<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>HAM,</hi> extending 5 Furlongs on the Road, the City it ſelf lying on the Right, Emi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nently ſituate upon (and almoſt encom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſt by) the River <hi>Were;</hi> a neat com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pact Place, accounting 6 Pariſh-Churches and a Cathedral: ′Tis Wall'd about, Strengthned with a Caſtle; Govern'd by a Mayor, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and well ſupply'd with Proviſions of all kinds.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="43" facs="tcp:108134:25"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 263′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You have the Gallows on the Left, and <hi>Cokehal</hi> on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>263′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>A ſmall Aſcent conveys you to <hi>Dur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham Moor</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>266′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Plausworth</hi> a Village con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiguous on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>267′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Right acute.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>267′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Lumley Hall</hi> on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>278′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Cheſter in the Street</hi> of 4 Furl. Extent, an antient Thorough-fare Town, Seated on the Weſtern Banks of the <hi>Were,</hi> and upon the old <hi>Roman Street-Way.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>269′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Peloo</hi> Hall, and at 271 Miles, <hi>Birtley,</hi> each 2 Furlongs on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>274′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave the Beacon; and at 274′ 5. a Wind-Mill, both on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>275′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Redhough.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>You enter <hi>Gateſhead</hi> vulgo <hi>Gateſide,</hi> joyn'd to <hi>New-Caſtle</hi> by a ſtately Stone-Bridg over the Navigable <hi>Tine;</hi> having paſt which, you enter <hi>Northumberland,</hi> and withall, <hi>New-Caſtle upon Tine:</hi> A Town and County as well as the Shire-Town, large, ſtrong, Rich and Populous; driving a great Trade by Sea and Land, eſpecially in Coals: Is Govern'd by a Mayor, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Sends Burgeſſes to Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment; hath 2 great Markets Weekly, and gives Title to His Grace, <hi>William Caven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diſh,</hi> Duke, Marqueſs and Earl of <hi>New-Caſtle.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>276′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave the Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="44" facs="tcp:108134:26"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 277′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Old Heton,</hi> and at 278′ 6. <hi>Great Bentham,</hi> each about a quarter of a Mile on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>280′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>North-Gosford</hi> a Village of 2 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>285′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Having before paſt between <hi>Bladedon</hi> and <hi>Shotton,</hi> you come to <hi>Blith-Bridg</hi> over the River <hi>Blith,</hi> which riſing about 5 Miles higher, receives the <hi>Pont</hi> (from the <hi>Picts</hi> Wall) a little above this Place, and at <hi>Blith</hi>'s <hi>Newk</hi> falls into the Sea.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>286′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Stannington</hi> a Village of 2 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs Extent.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>289′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Catchborn Caſtle</hi> a little on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>290′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Left to <hi>Shields.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>290′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Wanspeck,</hi> Seated on the River <hi>Wanspeck,</hi> which (riſing about 8 Miles higher) receives the <hi>Font</hi> a little above this Place, and 5 Miles lower falls into the Sea; over which a Stone-Bridg leads you into <hi>Morpeth,</hi> a Corporation, Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket and Poſt-Town, of 4 Furlongs Extent; Elects Parliament Men, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>291′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave the Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>292′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave <hi>Heborn,</hi> and at 295′ 0. <hi>Espe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ley,</hi> each half a Mile on the Left, and croſs the ſmall River <hi>Line.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>292′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left acute.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>301′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Cocket</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs, at the End of which, over <hi>Felton-Bridg,</hi> you croſs the River <hi>Cocket,</hi> which riſing on the Borders of <hi>Scotland,</hi> receives the <hi>
                              <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſway,
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:108134:26"/> Ridley</hi> and <hi>Ridland,</hi> embracing the Sea near <hi>Cocket</hi> Iſland.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 301′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Felton</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>302′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Acton</hi> 2 Furl. on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>304′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Newton on the Moor</hi> a Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lage contiguous on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>308′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through a ſmall Wood and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver a Rill or two.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>309′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>** Avoid the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>309′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Alnwick</hi> of 2 Furlongs Extent, Seated on the South Side of the River <hi>Alne;</hi> a Market-Town, ſhewing the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mains of a once large Caſtle and Abby.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>310′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the <hi>Alne,</hi> riſing about 10 Miles Eaſtward, and falling into the Sea at <hi>Ayl<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mouth</hi> about 5 Miles below.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>311′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>** Avoid the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend again the like quantity.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>312′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left acute.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>312′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>** Avoid the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>315′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Carleton</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>315′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left acute.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>319′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>** Leave the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>319′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Warnford</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs, Seated near the ſmall River <hi>Warne,</hi> four Miles from it's Influx into the Sea.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Edderſton</hi> a Furl. on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>321′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Right acute.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>322′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave <hi>Mowſewel</hi> 2 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>323′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Newland</hi> 2 Furlongs on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="46" facs="tcp:108134:27"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 323′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Belford</hi> a Poſt-Town of reaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able Reception.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>324′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave the Chapel a Furlong on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>326′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave <hi>Midleton</hi> about 3 Furlongs; and at 327′ 6. <hi>Detcham</hi> 2 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>328′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Buckton</hi> a Village conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guous on the Right, 12 Furlongs diſtant from the Sea, and oppoſite to <hi>Holy Iſland.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>329′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Fennick</hi> a Village 2 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>330′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Right acute.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>331′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Haggerſton</hi> a Village of 2 Furl.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>332′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Broom-Houſe,</hi> and at 333 Miles <hi>Bridg-Mill,</hi> each a ſmall diſtance on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>334′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave <hi>Cheſwick,</hi> and at 335′ 6. <hi>Skrimerſton,</hi> each about 3 Furlongs on the Left, and a Mile from the Sea Side.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>334′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Left acute.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>338′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You enter <hi>Twedemouth</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>338′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Right to <hi>Cailſho</hi> and <hi>Jedbrough,</hi> and ſo to <hi>CARLISLE.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>338′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Barwick</hi> Bridg over the fair and Navigable <hi>Tweed,</hi> which riſing in <hi>Scotland,</hi> receives One and Twenty Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers or Prime Branches, and about fif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen Miles higher becoming the Limits of the two Kingdoms, diſchargeth it ſelf into the Seat at this Place.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>339′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Barwick,</hi> or <hi>Berwick,</hi> a Town
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:108134:27"/> and County of great Strength, Natural<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Fortify'd by the Sea and River <hi>Tweed,</hi> and Artificially by a Wall and Caſtle; Is a large, Populous, and well-built Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poration and Market-Town; Electing Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament Men, and well ſerv'd with all ſorts of Proviſions.</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="48" facs="tcp:108134:28"/>
               <head>Direct Independants. <hi>Iter</hi> IV. The Road from <hi>LONDON</hi> to <hi>BRISTOL.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>The General Account.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell>1. THE Point of Bearing</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>W.</hi> b. <hi>N.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>2. The Direct Horizontal Diſtance</cell>
                        <cell>107 M.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>3. The Vulgar Computation</cell>
                        <cell>94 M.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>4. The Dimenſuration</cell>
                        <cell>115′ 2.</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>Counties Paſs'd through are, <hi>Midleſex, Bucking<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hamſhire, Barkſh. Wiltſh. Gloceſterſh.</hi> and <hi>Somerſetſh.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Rivers Croſs'd over are, the <hi>Brent, Coln, Thames, Kennet</hi> and <hi>Avon.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>The Journal.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="label">M. F.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 00′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>THE Standard in <hi>Cornhil,</hi> whence you proceed through <hi>Cornhil,</hi> the <hi>Poul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, Cheapſide,</hi> St. <hi>Pauls Church-Yard, Lud-Gate Street, Ludgate,</hi> down <hi>Lud-Gate Hill,</hi> through <hi>Fleet-Street, Temple-Bar,</hi> the <hi>Strand,</hi> the <hi>Hay-Market,</hi> and <hi>Pickadilly.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>02′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Begins St. <hi>James</hi>'s Park Wall on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>02′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>The Buildings terminate on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="49" facs="tcp:108134:28"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 03′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Over a Stone-Bridg you paſs a Rill ſupplying the <hi>Cana'l</hi> in St. <hi>James</hi>'s Park.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>03′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave St. <hi>James</hi>'s Park aforeſaid, by the Side whereof, the Way to <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> by St. <hi>James</hi>'s-<hi>Street, Petty-France,</hi> and <hi>Tuttle-Street</hi> turns down on the Left, and <hi>Hide-Park</hi> begins on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>03′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Knightsbridg</hi> a ſmall Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lage.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>04′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Hide-Park</hi> terminates, where entring <hi>Kenſington</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs, you paſs by the preſent Lord Keepers Houſe on the Right; and paſſing the Church, at the other End of the Town <hi>Campden</hi>-Houſe.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>05′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave the Earl of <hi>Holland</hi>'s Houſe 2 Furlongs on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>06′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Hamerſmith</hi> of 5 Furlongs Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent, Seated near the Banks of the <hi>Thames;</hi> in the Summer poſſeſt chiefly by the Gentry and Citizens.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>07′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Leave <hi>Cheſwick</hi> 3 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>07′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Turnham Green,</hi> paſſing the Wind-Mill on the Right, and the Houſes on the Left, you have at the far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther End, the Seats of the Marqueſs of <hi>Worceſter</hi> and Lord <hi>Crofts.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>08′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs by a fair Seat of Sr. <hi>John Mainards</hi> a Furl. on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>09′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Old Brentford,</hi> ſituate on the ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Brink of the <hi>Thames,</hi> and extending 4 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>09′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>New Brentford</hi> of 4 Furlongs like
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:108134:29"/> wiſe; a good Market-Town, at the End of which you croſs the <hi>Brent,</hi> riſing a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout <hi>Edgworth</hi> towards <hi>Hartfordſhire,</hi> and here embracing the <hi>Thames.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 10′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave the ſtately <hi>Sion-Houſe,</hi> and at 10′ 7. <hi>Iſtleworth</hi> Church, each 2 Furl. on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>11′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Small-beer Green.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>12′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Hounſlow</hi> of 4 Furl. length, a well-accomodated Thorough-fare.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>* At the End of the Town, the Left or forward Way leads to <hi>Stanes.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>12′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You enter <hi>Hounſlow Heath,</hi> diſtinguiſh'd into one, two, and three Mile Heaths; leaving <hi>Harlington</hi> about half a Mile on the Right, giving Title to the Right Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norable <hi>Henry Bennet,</hi> Earl of <hi>Arlington,</hi> &amp;c.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>16′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Longford</hi> a Village of 4 Furlongs, and croſs 4 ſeparated Bran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ches of the <hi>Coln,</hi> and among them, the <hi>Cut</hi> that ſupplies the <hi>Cana'l</hi> at <hi>Hampton Court.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>18′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the <hi>Coln,</hi> which riſing about the <hi>Hempſteds</hi> in <hi>Hartfordſhire,</hi> receives the <hi>Ver</hi> (from <hi>Verulam</hi> by St. <hi>Albans</hi>) at <hi>Rickmanſworth;</hi> when limiting <hi>Midle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſex</hi> from <hi>Buckinghamſhire;</hi> It paſſes by <hi>
                              <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>xbridg</hi> and this Place, and a little a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove <hi>Stanes</hi> falls into the <hi>Thames.</hi> Here you enter <hi>Colnbrook</hi> of near 4 Furlongs, a Market-Town, full of Inns, and of ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry good Reception.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="51" facs="tcp:108134:29"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 19′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Way on the Left is the Way by <hi>Datchet-Ferry</hi> to <hi>Windſor;</hi> Dignify'd with a ſtately Caſtle, the Kings Pallace, St. <hi>George</hi>'s Chapel, a College, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and here is kept the ſplendid Feaſt at the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtallation of Knights of the <hi>Garter.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>21′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave <hi>
                              <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pton</hi> 2 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>22′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Slow,</hi> a Village with ſome Inns, in which the Road to <hi>Windſor,</hi> by <hi>Eaton College,</hi> turns down on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>27′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Having firſt paſt by <hi>Burnham, Hicham,</hi> and <hi>Toplar</hi> Churches ſucceſſively, about 3 Furl. diſtance; leave Sr. <hi>Denis Hamptons</hi> Houſe on the Right alſo, and over a fair Wooden-Bridg croſs the <hi>Thames</hi> and enter <hi>Barkſhire,</hi> an Earldom in the Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of <hi>Charles Howard</hi> Earl of <hi>Barkſhire.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>27′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Maidenhead</hi> of 4 Furl. length, a very conſiderable Market-Town for Corn, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>28′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>* The great Road to <hi>Gloceſter</hi> by <hi>Hen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ley,</hi> &amp;c. bears forward to the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>30′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You enter <hi>Maidenhead-Thicket.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>31′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>** An obtuſe Way from <hi>Merloe</hi> falls in on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>33′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Harehatch</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>33′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>* The acute Way on the Right leads to <hi>Wargrave.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>35′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Twiford</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs and good Accomodation.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>35′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the <hi>Loddon,</hi> which riſing in <hi>Hampſhire,</hi> receives the <hi>Ditford,</hi> and di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viding
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:108134:30"/> it ſelf here into 4 Branches, falls into the <hi>Thames</hi> about 2 Miles below.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 36′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>* The acute Way on the Right leads to <hi>Sunning,</hi> a Market-Town about a Mile diſtant.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>39′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>** Falls in an obtuſe Way on the Left from <hi>Ockingham,</hi> another Market-Town, about 4 Miles diſtant.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>39′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Reading,</hi> Seated on the <hi>Kennet,</hi> near It's Conflux with the <hi>Thames;</hi> a fair Corporation and Market-Town, of 5 Furlongs Extent, with 3 Churches, and the Election of Parliament Men.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>43′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>* Upon <hi>Tyleherſt Heath</hi> you omit the acute Way on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>44′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>** An obtuſe Way falls in on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>You enter <hi>Theal,</hi> i. e. <hi>The Vale,</hi> a ſcat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tering Town of 3 Furlongs; at the End of which you leave <hi>Inglefield,</hi> the Seat of the Marqueſs of <hi>Wincheſter,</hi> half a Mile on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>50′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Deſcend a little Hill, and enter <hi>Wool<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hampton</hi> vulgo <hi>Wollington,</hi> a Village of 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>53′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Thatcham</hi> of 3 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>55′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You have the <hi>Kennet</hi> cloſe on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>56′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Spinhamland,</hi> that Part of <hi>New<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bury</hi> ſo call'd; whence a fair Street on the Left leads to <hi>Newbury,</hi> pleaſantly Seated on the foreſaid <hi>Kennet;</hi> a Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poration and Market-Town, with a Free-School, 3 Alms-Houſes, and an Hoſpital.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>57′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Spein</hi> a Village contigu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:108134:30"/> on the Left, aſcending gently, two Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 58′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>You have <hi>Craven Park</hi> on the Left, and <hi>Wickham Heath</hi> or <hi>Common</hi> on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>59′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend 3 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>62′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>* The forward Way proceeds directly to <hi>Hungerford.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>64′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs through a ſmall Wood.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>65′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Wiltſhire.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>65′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>* The forward, or Right-Hand Way leads to <hi>Lamborn.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>66′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Chilton</hi> a diſcontinued Town of 4 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>67′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave <hi>Littlecote Houſe</hi> 3 Furlongs on the Left, on the other ſide of the <hi>Ken<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>net.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>69′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Ramesbury</hi> a ſcattering Town of 4 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>70′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You paſs cloſe by <hi>Ramesbury Manor,</hi> the Earl of <hi>Pembroke</hi>'s, on the Left; where you aſcend gently 2 Furlongs, equally de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcending.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>71′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>* The acute Way on the left yields a different Road to <hi>Marlborough.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>72′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You have a ſmall Wood on your Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>72′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You aſcend 2 Furlongs and a Chalk-Hill; at 73′ 1. paſſing through Woody Land, deſcend again.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>73′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Mildenhal</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>74′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>** An obtuſe Way on the Right falls in from <hi>OXFORD.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>75′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>By riſing Ground enter <hi>Marlborough,</hi>
                           <pb n="54" facs="tcp:108134:31"/> 2 Furl. more bringing you to the Market-Houſe, where comes in the Coach-Way to <hi>BATH,</hi> and the Way by <hi>Hungerford;</hi> extending in the Whole 6 Furlongs: A Corporation and Market-Town, Electing Burgeſſes to Parliament; and giving Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle to the Right Honorable <hi>William Ley,</hi> Earl of <hi>Marlborough.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>But proſecuting the directer Way by <hi>Hungerford,</hi> from 62′ 2.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 64′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the <hi>Kennet,</hi> and at once enter <hi>Wiltſhire</hi> and <hi>Charnam-Street,</hi> that Part of <hi>Hungerford</hi> ſo call'd; the Town it ſelf extending 4 Furlongs on the Left; a Market and Poſt-Town.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>67′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>* You have an acute Way on the Right to <hi>Froxfield</hi> and <hi>Ramesbury.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>67′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You have <hi>Froxfield</hi> Church on the Right 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>69′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You enter <hi>Savernake Foreſt.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>71′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You aſcend eaſily 7 Furlongs; and at 72′ 6. deſcend again 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>73′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You croſs the <hi>Kennet</hi> and enter <hi>Marl<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>borough;</hi> 2 Furl. more bringing you to the Market-Houſe and Croſs-Way aforeſaid; ſo that this Way is leſs by 11 Furlongs than by <hi>Ramesbury:</hi> But proceeding,</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>75′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Accounted by <hi>Ramesbury,</hi> you leave <hi>Marlborough</hi> and the Duke of <hi>Somerſet</hi>'s Houſe and Mount on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>76′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You leave <hi>Preſhuter</hi> Church, and after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards <hi>Manton</hi> and <hi>Clatford</hi> about 2 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs on the Left, all beyond the River.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <pb n="55" facs="tcp:108134:31"/>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 78′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You Leave <hi>Fifield</hi> 2 Furlongs on the ſame Hand, on this ſide the <hi>Kennet.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>78′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>79′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>(Having aſcended 2 Furlongs) you de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcend the like quantity.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>80′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Little Kennet</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>81′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>* You Ride cloſe under <hi>Sidbury Hill,</hi> an artificial Mount; where the Road to the <hi>Devizes</hi> branches out on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>81′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Beckhampton</hi> vulgo <hi>Beck<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ington,</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>82′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>* Being entred <hi>Marlbrough Downs,</hi> the Road to <hi>BATH</hi> by <hi>Sandy Lane,</hi> bears forward on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>85′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>Having paſt two Aſcents and one De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcent, you leave <hi>Cheril</hi> a Furlong on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>87′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Cumberford</hi> Bridg over the River <hi>Coln.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>87′ 6.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Caln,</hi> Seated on the foreſaid <hi>Coln,</hi> of 5 Furlongs extent; a Market-Town, with the Election of Parliament Men; to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the farther End of which, the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Way on the Right leads to <hi>Malmſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bury.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>89′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Studley</hi> Bridg over the foreſaid <hi>Coln;</hi> whence you aſcend 3 Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>90′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Studley</hi> a Village.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>90′ 7.</cell>
                        <cell>** An obtuſe Way from the <hi>Devizes</hi> falls in on the Left, where you deſcend 2 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>63′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Chipenham,</hi> of 7 Furlongs length,
<pb facs="tcp:108134:32"/> Seated on the <hi>Avon,</hi> which you croſs in the Town over a fair Stone-Bridg; a Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket-Town, with the Election of Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers to Parliament.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>At 93′ 3.</cell>
                        <cell>* A little beyond the Bridg, the Road to <hi>BATH</hi> by <hi>Pickwick,</hi> &amp;c. turns out on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>96′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>* The Right-Hand Way leads to <hi>Sodbu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry,</hi> and thence over into <hi>Wales</hi> by <hi>Auſt-Ferry.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>98′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend 3 Furlongs, and at 98′ 7. aſcend alike, leaving <hi>Caſtle-Comb</hi> a Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket-Town, about 2 Miles on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>100′ 3</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Wraxhal</hi> Church cloſe on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>101′ 3</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Gloceſterſhire.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>102′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>Enter <hi>Marſhfield</hi> 4 Furlongs in length, bleakly ſituate on the <hi>Wolds,</hi> with a great Corn-Market.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>104′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Cold Aſton</hi> Church 2 Furlongs on the Left.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>106′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You deſcend <hi>Tug-Hill</hi> of 3 Furlongs.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>107′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Plough-Way falls in on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>107′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>** A Road from <hi>BATH</hi> falls in on the Left</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>108′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>You aſcend 3 Furlongs deſcending alike.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>109′ 1.</cell>
                        <cell>** An obtuſe Way from <hi>Deinton</hi> falls in on the Right.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>110′ 4.</cell>
                        <cell>Aſcend <hi>Barton Hill</hi> for 6 Furlongs, pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſſing through <hi>Kingſwood</hi> and by the Coal-Pits.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>113′ 0.</cell>
                        <cell>You come to <hi>Dungeon Croſs.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>114′ 2.</cell>
                        <cell>** An obtuſe Way from <hi>Stapleton</hi> falls
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:108134:32"/> in on the Right, where you enter the Suburbs of the City of <hi>BRISTOL.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>14′ 5.</cell>
                        <cell>** The Road from <hi>GLOCESTER</hi> falls in on the Right, and you arrive at <hi>Lawfords-Gate,</hi> whence through <hi>Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fords Street, Caſtle-Gate,</hi> and <hi>Vine-Street,</hi> you Meaſure 115′ 2. to the High-Croſs of the City.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>BRISTOL,</hi> a City and County, Seat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed on the River <hi>Avon;</hi> large, Populous and well Built, eſteemed the Second of the Kingdom for Trade and Traffique; contains 18 Pariſh-Churches beſides the Cathedral; made an Epiſcopal See by King <hi>H.</hi> 8. Wall'd about; Govern'd by a Mayor, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Sends Burgeſſes to Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament; and gives Title to the Right Honorable <hi>George Digby</hi> Earl of <hi>Briſtol.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
